CMA SUMAN SIROHI

A competent professional with **5 years** of consistent success in maximizing financial performance. Distinction of being an **Associate Member of "The Institute of Cost Accountants of India" Formerly Known As "ICWAI" and formerly associated with Rajeev Sharma &**

"Audit

Manager"

as

Contact:

Address:

INA Dilli Haat, New Delhi-110023 India

Phone:

08587892058

Email:

Sumansirohi001@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cma-suman-sirohi-b95647133

Personal Dossier

Date of Birth: 25th October 1985 Father Name: Sripal Sirohi

Languages

English

Hindi

Hobbies

- Reading
- Travelling
- Listening Music
- Watching Movies

Skill Highlights

Summary

Associates

- Finance & Accounts
- Cost Data Verification
- Taxation
- MIS Reporting

Academic Credentials

CMA(ICWA)-Institute of Cost Accountants of India (ICAI), Delhi in 2017.

- □ **B.Com.** from Delhi University in 2010.
- □ **12th** from C.B.S.E.,2004.
- □ **10th** from C.B.S.E.,2002.

Technical Skill

- □ Enterprise resource planning (ERP)- **Oracle 11i & R12**
- ☐ MS Office (Word, Excel and PowerPoint).
- ☐ Accounting software viz., **Tally ERP**

Training Attended

- ☐ Goods & Service Tax (GST)-Certification Program from Thinking Bridge.
- ☐ Training of "Computer Software in Accounts and Finance" and "Information Technology for Auditing and Cost Management" from I.C.A.I., Delhi.

Page

Experience

Rajeev Sharma & Associates

Audit Manager - 09/2018 to 10/2020

Key Deliverables:

- Accounting Entries in Tally, Profit & Loss and Balance sheet preparation, GST Registration, GST return filing, Income tax return, Company registration at MCA, Apply PAN/TAN, etc.
- Examination of Annual Progress Report (APR) of SEZ & EOU units. Follow up action in respect of deficient APRs by way of Notices to the defaulters/non-filers.
- Scrutiny of QPRs and Half Yearly reports including verification of Utilization Certificate submitted by the SEZ Developers/Co-Developers for placing before the Approval Committee.
- Scrutiny of the value of the Capital Goods and the materials including verification of the total calculation.
- ➤ Written opinions required by different level of commissioners (Deputy Commissioner of customs, Joint Development Commissioner, Deputy Development commissioners, Assistant Development Commissioner) in respect of issues related to APR/Balance sheet or any other financial accounting matters.
- Uploading Data of APR/Utilization Certificate in the software.
- > Calculations of the Value Additions in case of the Gems & Jewellery Units and submission of reports thereof in terms of the prevailing norms.
- Preparation of reports for the Monitoring of the EOU Units in the various Commissionerates.
- Providing records to CAG Auditors and making reply for observations.

Santosh Kumar & Co.

Cost Audit Assistant-03/2017 to 09/2018

<u>Key Deliverables:</u>

- Posting journal entries in Tally ERP
- Income tax return filing
- GST return filing
- Profit & Loss statement and Balance Sheet preparation
- Cost sheet preparation

FICC Dept. (Govt of India)

Cost Evaluation-Consultant-09/2016 to 03/2017

Key Deliverables:

- Evaluation of cost data submitted to the Ministry by different fertilizer companies
- Examine the reasonability of MRP of different products fixed by the company
- Critically examine different elements of cost sheet of the products like total cost of Production, administration cost, interest and finance charges etc.
- > Compare the profit/loss of different companies to ensure the company is not earning abnormal profit.
- Analyze the cost audit reports submitted to the ministry by different cost accountants
- Verify the working of the cost audit reports
- Maintaining the cost data submitted by the different companies in excel formats and report it to the concerned officer
- Reconciliation of cost profit with financial profit

MARUTI SUZUKI INDIA LIMITED

Industrial Trainee -02/2014 to 02/2015

Key Deliverables:

- > Preparation of Bank Reconciliation of different banks with GL on a daily basis
- Preparation& Reconciliation of Dealers Accounts & Reporting to Management on a daily basis Handling of Export Remittance and Earnest Money Deposit (EMD) matters
- Preparation of Dealer Balance confirmation report on half yearly basis
- Preparation of Pay in Slip(PIS) and Making Monthly closing accounting entries in ERP(Oracle)
- Posting journal entries in ERP Oracle